Hey everyone, let's go ahead and get started with the Langegraf
fundamentals. So before we get started with the Langegraf fundamentals you have
to understand what is the flow engineering and the finite state
machine. Basically this overall LAN graph is based on the flow engineering and the
finite state machine itself. There are three main components in the Langegraf
which we have to understand. One is the state, then we have a node, and then we
have the ages. Once you understand these three concepts, then learning line graph
is going to be super easy for you. It is going to be effortless for you. I have
shown here a figure which explains all these three concepts state, node, and age.
Here there is a user. User sends a message that goes to the start node. And then
there is the process input node, add prefix, add suffix, and the end node. So this is
the custom flow which I am showing you. In this particular flow we have a three node.
These are the custom built node and there are two other node which are actually
ready or you can say the pre-built node from the line graph itself. Any graph
starts with the start itself and it ends at the end node. So these are the default
node which comes from the line graph itself. Other than that you can make as many node
you want and you can connect these nodes together using the AJCL. You can also put
the conditional statements as well in between if you want. Later on in this
course we will be seeing how you can do those things as well.
Other things are here like that is the state. So state is going to have here a
dictionary that is going to be named as the messages. By default in the messages
you are going to have human message itself. Whatever the query comes from the
user that that is the human message. Then there is the process input node that
generates the message that becomes the message one or the AI message. Then there
is the another message that is the m2. So as your line graph generates the
messages all those are going to be added here. Let's try to understand the finite
state machine with some concept. There is very famous example eat sleep and code. In this
example you have a three node. So basically in one node you eat and thereafter you have two
more node where you either sleep or your code. So I can say that here it is going to be the sleep.
And the third node I can say that it is about the code. Let's go ahead and quickly name these
change the color. So this one I am going to do this color and this one I am going to do this one.
All right. So when do you sleep? Once you feel tired then you sleep. So I can connect
these together. I can say that okay here you have all these okay. Thereafter
when do you code? While you are sleeping when you awake you are in awake state then you code.
And then while you are doing coding and if you feel hungry thereafter you eat here. So what you can say
here that this part this one particularly you can name as when you feel tired then you sleep. And while
sleeping once you are awake I mean after sleeping then you start coding again.
And if you feel hungry then what you do here you again code. So this is one way to do this.
This cycle can be also reversed here as well. So like you can also do the coding after eating itself.
So in that way once you are full of eating basically once you feel full while eating or after eating then
you can do the coding as well. After eating if you feel tired then you can also sleep here as well.
All right. In fact this part we have already covered here. We have to cover the reverse version here.
While you sleep once you feel hungry then you can say that you can eat again. All right.
So basically I can say that this is going to eat here.
And then we have to also connect here this one reversely like this one. So while coding if you
feel tired then what you do you go and sleep. So this whole thing what you see here this you can
say that the finite state machine. So in finite state machine what happen here there are certain
and predefined or you can say the finite number of the states. So these are three states here. All right.
Eat sleep and the code. In our line graph we say that these are node actually. All right. So we have
node 1 which we can say that this is going to be the node 1.
node 1. You can say that this is going to be the node 2.
And then you also have here the node 3.
And these connecting edges are known as the age here. And these numbers what you see here these are
actually the state. So a person eat and thereafter once he feels tired then the person goes to sleep.
And if it is awake then comes and code. So this is like a you know pure software developer architecture.
So this is how you can understand that what is the finite state machine.
So this is very fundamental into the concept in the line graph. This is what we will be using throughout
this course. Where we will be making so many nodes. And also we will be connecting all those nodes together
with the edges. And also we are going to manage the state. So this is like you know the default state
available with the line graph. That is the messages state. So messages are like this. Where it starts
with the human message first of all. Thereafter as your line graph generates the messages. It is going to
add messages in the list here itself. It starts with the human message. Then the first message
comes. Second message comes. All those messages are going to be added here. So this is like appending
in already existing list. So as your conversation moves forward you are also maintaining here the history
as well. So this is like having the historical data together as well. In our langchain course. In fact in
our langchain introduction part as well. We had seen there the output was coming just as the last
AI message. So whenever we had invoked our lm.invoke then we were getting the last AI message only.
But in case of the lang graph, lang graph is designed in such a way that it can also maintain
maintain the historical conversations as well. All right. So this is the basic building block of the
lang graph. I hope that you have understood that how overall lang graph works. Now in the coming lessons
we will start with the coding part. All right. I'll see you then.